

Arslan Arif

Artificial Intelligence Engineer

Address: Satellite Town, Rawalpindi Pakistan

Cell/WhatsApp: +923445704045

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/lamArslanArif

Email: arslankhan965@gmail.com

PROFILE

I am an AI Engineer with 3 years of professional experience with expertise in python, machine learning and natural language processing. I have worked on a variety of AI projects including computer vision and facial recognition systems, AI chatbots, data scraping, content aggregation, text classification, sentiment analysis and reinforcement learning agents to name a few. I have also worked on web apps and web services and have experience in the Django Rest framework. I have excellent problem-solving skills with strong basics in programming, data structures and OOP as well as data science, statistics and mathematics. I have the ability to quickly adapt to new tools and technologies.

EXPERIENCE

Artificial Intelligence Engineer - RNS Solutions, Rawalpindi

[May 2021 - Present]

- Designed and developed an educational chatbot using ML and NLP techniques.
- Performed text pre-processing and prepared datasets for text classification models.
- Developed a web-based system in django rest framework to perform data manipulation and unique data analysis for NLP projects.
- Developed an object detection and OCR based system to detect, extract and parse different parts of text message screenshots from smartphones.
- Developed an AI crypto trading bot using reinforcement learning techniques.
- Deployed different AI based solutions in production using docker and aws.

Software Engineer (Python AI/NLP) - <u>Tech Avenue Pvt Ltd, Islamabad</u>

[July 2019 - April 2021]

- Analysed complex computer vision problems, designed and developed surveillance systems using facial recognition and tracking.
- Designed and developed content aggregator solutions by the means of web scraping.
- Used text analysis, classification, trend and sentiment analysis to develop an intelligent real-time news aggregator system.
- Designed and deployed complex databases for different projects in NoSQL database systems as well as relational database systems.
- Participated in the development of big data softwares using Hadoop/HDFS, HBase and other big data applications.

Jr. Android Developer - Invotyx, Rawalpindi

[July 2018 - November 2018]

• Developed android IOT applications to control different smart home devices.

 Developed android utility apps like chatbot messengers, photo editors and photo filter apps as per requirements and specifications.

SOFT SKILLS

Communication Persuasion Collaboration Problem Solving Critical Thinking

Adaptability Leadership Team Management Creativity Emotional Intelligence

TECHNOLOGY STACK

Languages and DBs

- Python
- Java
- C#
- C/C++
- JavaScript
- jQuery
- MongoDB
- SQL Server
- SQLite
- Elastic Search
- Hadoop/HDFS
- HBase

Frameworks/Libraries

- Pandas, Numpy
- Tensorflow
- PyTorch
- Rasa
- Tesseract
- OpenCV
- Scrapy
- Beautiful Soup
- Stale Baselines
- Open Al gym envs
- Django
- Flask

Other Skills

- Design Patterns
- REST APIs
- Socket Programming
- Multithreading and Multiprocessing.
- Openstreet Maps
- GPS, Positioning and routes
- Git/Version Control
- Bitbucket/Jira
- Docker
- AWS compute/store

EDUCATION

BS Computer Science [2015 - 2019]

Quaid-i-Azam University, Islamabad

Final Year Project - Smart Gallery

- Developed an AI based photo gallery with the feature of visual image search.
- The app uses tf-lite object detection model to recognize objects and provides a visual search option to the users.

LANGUAGES

- English (Professional)
- Urdu (Native)

INTERESTS/HOBBIES

- Self educating myself about religion, science, history, social affairs, education, economy, diplomacy, political systems and ideologies, geographies and cultures.
- Study and write literature and poetry.
- Networking with different types of people for professional growth and PR.
- Participating in volunteer social works.

REFERENCES

References will be provided if required.